[theme music playing]
The land we're planning to use
is currently occupied by the farmers.
But don't worry, we'll force them out.
[Ivy] What?! I don't want
to be involved in that.
We can't force them out.
-[Diego] What are you doing?
-[cop] We're following orders.
Are you ordered to hurt people, huh?!
Salvage our crops!
We don't need your help!
Don't try to fool the farmers.
You're only after the land, right?!
I just want to help.
You want to help? Then leave Ardiente!
You're smart enough to see that.
And you're beautiful too.
It's a shame you don't have a good heart.
[Jepoy] Someone saw you
destroying the statue.
[Ivy] What?! Who saw me?
[Jepoy] His name is Arthur. He's nuts.
I found these in his house.
[Ivy] These are my father's files.
[Julio] Where is this man right now?
[Dimalanta] He's been detained,
Congressman.
Can you bring him here?
-And burn all the evidence.
-[Dimalanta] Yes, sir.
I thought you'd already silenced that man.
Do you really think a lunatic like him
is capable of doing all this alone?!
[Arthur] The savior has arrived
to destroy you all!
[Arnaldo] No one messes
with my grandfather!
[Diego] Whatever it is you're up to,
I hope you think it over.
[Arnaldo] I'm the mayor. And you?
[Diego] I'm the Ardiente
who cares for the people.
[Ivy] You just need to stand your ground.
Maybe it's time for you to show
that you can play their game,
not as a woman, but as their equal.
[Emilia laughing]
[sighs]
-I better get going.
-[both chuckling]
Thank you, Ivy.
Thank you for all your pieces of advice.
I'll keep them in mind.
Thank you.
Actually, you didn't need my advice.
All you needed was a wake-up call.
Let's go!
-[laughing hysterically]
-[Ivy] Oh!
-[Emilia] I'm really drunk.
-[Ivy chuckling]
You know what? Uh…
All right, I'll drive you home.
Aww. Thank you, Ivy.
You're really a good friend.
Thank you!
Thank you.
-Anytime.
-[giggles]
I'm sorry. I'm really drunk.
-So, shall we go?
-[Ivy] Yeah.
[sighs]
Stay away from us!
We don't need your help!
[Ivy] Mr. Torillo, I'm here
because I want to help.
You want to help?!
Then leave Ardiente!
[Julio] I would like
to personally thank Miss Aguas
for her investment
in the export processing zone
in this town.
What is she really here for?
[tense music swelling]
[car revving]
[tense music playing]
[Ivy] I could end your life
right now, Emilia.
But you don't deserve a quick death.
I want you to suffer piece by piece.
[grunting]
[groans loudly]
[gasps]
[gasps and grunts]
Listen to me.
I'll let you escape.
Hide and don't ever come back, okay?
Copy.
[Arnaldo] Hey! Is everything all right?
Make sure that those knots are tight.
-All good, Mayor.
-[grunts]
-[Arnaldo] Good.
-[whimpers]
Put this on him.
[Arthur whimpering] Please, no!
Oh! No need to be scared.
It's your own pack of dynamite.
I'll just use it on you.
[Arthur wailing]
-[Arnaldo] Go on.
-No!
-[Arnaldo chuckling]
-[Arthur gasping]
[Arthur] No!
-[grunts]
-[Arnaldo] Tie it around.
[gasps and whimpers]
-[groans]
-[Arnaldo] You done?
[Arthur wailing]
[Arthur] No!
[Arthur whimpers]
Please don't!
[groans]
-Here, light it up!
-[Arthur] No!
No!
-[Arnaldo] Come on.
-No!
[Arthur wails]
[tense music playing]
[grunts]
[gasps]
[tense music playing]
[gunshots]
[screams]
[gasping]
A lunatic escaped me.
[laughs]
-That lunatic got away!
-[gunshots]
[Jepoy] He won't get that far, Mayor.
With those wounds, he'll be dead soon.
Thanks for saving me back there.
It's my fault. I wasn't careful
around that lunatic.
There's nothing we can do now.
But if the congressman asks…
if I've already dealt with Arthur…
do you know what to say?
You don't have to tell me.
Drive me home. After that…
you can do whatever you want.
[Emilia laughing]
Sorry, Ivy.
-[retches]
-Governor! Oh.
-[Emilia laughing]
-[Ivy] Be careful.
-Let's go here.
-Let's do that again.
[laughing]
-[Ivy] Governor.
-[Julio] Emilia!
[Emilia] Papa.
[Julio] Good evening, Miss Aguas.
[groaning]
Good evening, Congressman.
It looks like my daughter
enjoyed your company.
[sighs] Thank you for driving her home.
I think I can take it from here.
Are you sure, Congressman?
Of course.
She's already home.
I can handle this.
Thank you again.
Thank you.
All right, I'll go ahead.
[Julio] Sit down.
We have to talk.
As always…
-you're not using your brain!
-Ouch!
That hurts, Papa!
-[Julio] You imbecile!
-[Emilia] That hurts.
A woman like you,
getting drunk like that?!
-Show some dignity!
-[grunts]
-Huh!
[Julio] Use your brain!
Did you forget that you're the governor?
What if the people see you like this?
Do you think they'd respect you, huh?!
-Go inside!
-[Emilia grunts]
Go straight to your room!
[grunts]
-You have no self-respect!
-[grunts]
I don't care about what people say!
[shouting] You are right!
I am the governor,
and I can do anything I want!
[tense music playing]
And when did you learn to talk back?!
You're drunk!
Go inside your--
-Go inside--
-[grunts]
I'm so sick of you!
Stop treating me like a puppet!
Starting now, I am in charge of my life!
[tense music playing]
[romantic music playing]
What are you doing here?
It's already late.
The offices of the executives
are already closed.
I just drove the governor home.
Also, why did you come
to my house earlier?
I wanted to talk to you.
Really? About what?
You know my intentions, Miss Aguas.
But remember this.
I'll do everything in my power
to defend the farmers' rights.
[Julio] Emilia…
since when did you have the guts
to fight back against me?!
[Emilia shouting] I'm so fed up with you!
I'm leaving, Mr. Torillo.
I am an Ardiente!
So treat me like an Ardiente!
I demand your respect!
[Julio] Demand?
You have no right to demand anything!
I will treat you
the way you deserve to be treated.
From the start through till now,
what I see you as is a weak woman.
A fly!
You're just a fly sitting on a cow's back.
So learn to stay in your proper place!
-[Emilia] That's enough!
-[Diego] Grandpa!
Stop it, Grandpa!
Let go, or you'll be punished too!
Let go!
I'm not leaving, and you won't hurt Mom!
[exhales]
Remember this, both of you!
We aren't done here!
Mom, are you okay?
Next time, don't defend me
because I can handle myself!
[Ivy] You should have seen
Julio and Emilia.
[scoffs]
Don't worry, dear.
When this is all over,
and you get your justice,
you can finally tell Diego the truth.
You'll both be free.
I hope when Diego finds the truth…
he'll understand why I did this.
[sighs] Let's not talk about Diego.
How's Jepoy? Any news about him?
He's not answering my calls.
Me too. I've been also trying,
but I can't reach him.
I'm starting to get worried!
[voice prompt] The subscriber
cannot be reached.
Please try again later.
[Ivy] Maybe it's time to show them
that you can play their game…
not as a woman, but as their equal.
As Governor Emilia, and as an Ardiente.
[Emilia] My father's crutches
won't bring me down.
I'm strong.
I'm stronger than before.
I shouldn't get myself hurt.
I can face anything.
[Ivy] He's not answering my calls.
-[Carlotta] Mine too.
-I should go--
[Carlotta] Oh!
[tender music playing]
What happened to you?!
We've been trying to reach you!
Why weren't you answering?!
I-- I couldn't pick up
because my phone broke earlier.
Are you fine? Are you wounded?
Were you hurt?
How are you feeling? Are you fine?
-Jepoy!
-I'm fine.
-I'm perfectly fine.
-[sighs deeply]
-I hope Arthur is also safe.
-Why, what happened to him?
[Jepoy] Arnaldo beat him up.
And even planned to blow Arthur up.
Good thing I let Arthur escape.
Are you sure you're fine?
[tender music playing]
[Emilia] My dear husband is finally home.
[Emilia chuckles softly]
Why are you home so late? You got held up?
[Raul] Yes, because we're out of men.
Tell your dad to hire more men
to make the work--
But you already know
that Papa won't entrust it
to anybody else.
He wants you to manage the business.
It's not easy to manage
the operations alone.
I need more men to help me.
And we need the money,
and you will deliver it to us, right?
Of course, but also talk to your father
so I won't be held up,
and you'll stop nagging me
for coming home late.
It's that easy.
-[Emilia] I know.
-Stop it.
I'm not in the mood. I'm tired, Emilia.
Tired because of work or your mistresses?!
Hold on. What's wrong with you?
Are you all right?
You're acting delirious.
I can smell the cheap perfume
on your skin!
[quietly] She doesn't wear perfume.
What did you say?!
-Nothing--
-[smooches]
[Raul] Emilia, stop.
This isn't funny anymore.
[Emilia yelps]
-What's your problem?
-You are my problem!
All these years, I'm enduring it all!
I enduring all the pain and neglect!
But not this time anymore.
Because you will fulfill
your obligations to me!
[Raul] Stop it!
-Will you stop?!
-[Emilia grunts]
I'm not playing games!
-Raul!
-[slams]
[Ivy] I've decided to hold off
my investment in the Ardientes
so that Arnaldo's project
will be postponed.
They might suspect you because of that.
I know, Jepoy.
That's why we're executing our next move.
It's time to publicly reveal
their true colors.
We've gathered enough evidence.
And don't forget my new friend…
Senator Pablo Alcantara.
I'm sure this issue
will reach the headlines
if his name is involved.
Hmm.
[Jepoy] Thanks.
Later, girls.
Where's the congressman's cut?
[man] Give him the congressman's share!
Who do you think
we should send it to first?
To our friends in the media?
Or to those who attended my party?
Or maybe…
[Raul] Where's the congressman's cut?
…to my closest connections?
It doesn't matter.
When the Ardientes wake up tomorrow…
they're going to face a nightmare.
[tense music playing]
[Julio] How much did you collect, Raul?
Two hundred fifty, Pa.
That's it?
That's the usual amount, isn't it?
But you were gone for two days.
What did you do? Go on vacation…
while we're stuck with our problems here?
Papa, can you please stop?
Raul did his best.
Let's just be thankful to him.
-Raul.
-Yes?
Say something.
Pa, first, the situation there
is not that simple.
That territory belongs
to your political rivals.
Good thing that your friend
in Senate is protecting us.
-[Julio scoffs]
-That's all.
That's the point.
You are protected under my name.
Meaning, you can freely move there.
So, don't give me that lame excuse.
Just admit…
that you had fun
with your cheap women again.
-[clatters]
-Papa, can you please stop?!
I've had enough of this!
Starting today,
only I can chastise my husband!
You have no right
to meddle in our affairs!
[tense music playing]
[maid] Senator, you have a visitor.
-Ah!
-Senator.
Miss Aguas, good morning. Please sit down.
So, what's the problem
that brought you here?
Haven't you heard?
Didn't you receive a video email?
Video? What video?
Senator, I received an email this morning.
I thought it was spam mail,
but when I opened it…
it was a sensitive video.
Now that intrigues me.
Um… Let me check my phone.
It might've slipped my eyes.
[grunting]
This is my house, Emilia!
I will scold anyone I want!
I will chastise anyone I want!
And there's nothing you can do about it.
You will regret
this disrespectful act of yours.
Because this is the last time…
that I tolerate you.
The next time you disrespect me…
I will forget that you're my daughter!
[tense music playing]
Let's enjoy the food. Just let him be.
One day, he'll realize
that anger and vexation
won't solve everything.
One can't force their way
to being relevant.
[tense music playing]
[Raul] Where's the congressman's cut?
[man 1] Give him the congressman's share!
[man 2] This is for the senator.
[man 1] Okay, include that one.
-[Raul] Is this all of it?
-[man 1] Yes, boss.
[indistinct chatter]
[tense music playing]
Are you sure about this, Jepoy?
[Jepoy] Just like the old times.
We both know the risks.
Thank you.
[woman] Who are you doing this for, Jepoy?
You don't have to know.
We're also paying for your silence.
Thanks, then. Until next time.
[tense music swelling]
Where did you get this video?
I just received an email this morning.
I'm sorry, Miss Aguas.
You have to leave now.
Uh… Okay, Senator.
But before I leave…
I have to return this to you.
I can't accept that anymore.
It's the check for the property
you bought at the auction.
Why?
Why?!
Come on, Senator.
I don't want to get involved
in that gambling issue.
For sure, the media will investigate
the source of your funds.
And they might trace that check.
So, you believe that video?
Senator, believe me, I'm trying not to.
But like what you said at the party,
you're close to Congressman.
If the issue spreads,
the media will swarm you,
especially because you passed
the Anti-Gambling Bill.
So, think about what people
will say, Senator.
The senator who authored
the Anti-Gambling Bill
is actually a gambling lord.
[scoffs] Senator, I'm sorry
if this is happening.
I'll get going.
But honestly…
if I were you, I'll distance myself
from Congressman.
Again, I'm sorry.
[tense music playing]
[reporter 1] Good morning, Congressman.
Good morning.
-[reporter 2] Good morning, sir.
-What brings you here?
[reporter 1] We just want
to know your opinion
about the controversial video.
[reporter 2] We just want
to hear your comment.
What video?
About your gambling scandal, sir.
Gambling scandal?!
What are you talking about?!
Here, sir.
-Uh…
-[reporter 1] What can you say?
Is it true that you are a gambling lord?
[Julio] I cannot answer you right now.
-Sir, we'd like to know--
-I have to go to the office.
-Wait, sir.
-We'd like to hear your side…
-[Julio] That's a lie.
-Are you a gambling lord?
-[Julio] No comment.
-[reporter 1] Sir! Congressman!
Just a few words, Congressman!
-I'm sorry!
-We'd like to hear your side.
[suspenseful sting]
[reporter] The family of Solon
Julio Ardiente draws flak
over a viral gambling scandal in his town.
It is believed that Rep. Ardiente himself
is the owner and operator
of the alleged big-time
gambling operation.
Senator Pablo Alcantara,
Rep. Ardiente's close friend,
refused to comment on the issue
as he is also tagged in the scandal.
It can be recalled that Sen. Alcantara
authored the Anti-Gambling Bill
in the Senate.
Now, many are wondering
if both men are working together
in these illegal operations
in Poblacion Ardiente.
Meddling bastards!
[spits]
Arnaldo, have you traced
the source of that email?!
Not yet. Our men are having
a hard time decrypting it.
Emilia, have you contacted Senator Pablo?
I've been trying to call him,
but he is not answering.
It looks like he's avoiding us!
His secretary told me
that the senator is busy.
Coward!
Damn it! You're all useless!
Don't blame this on us, Papa!
It's not our fault!
Arnaldo, contact the press.
I need to get to the media first
before Pablo does.
I have to contain this!
A press conference?!
Papa, a press conference
won't do you good!
What will you do?!
You will deny the video?! You will lie?!
Come on!
Papa, the best way to handle
things is to keep quiet!
Less talk, less mistakes!
-[Loring] Diego! Diego!
-[Diego] What is it?
Something happened!
The reporters are saying
that your grandfather
is a gambling lord!
[man] Is that true, Diego?
Everyone is innocent until proven guilty.
We shouldn't believe in rumors.
But don't worry,
I'll get to the bottom of this.
[laughs]
Terrific!
What would you like to happen?!
Do you want to ruin my reputation?!
Are you nuts?!
No! I will speak up!
And besides, I know
how to handle these things.
You have no right to dictate my decisions!
Arnaldo, contact the press.
Copy that.
Raul, you moron!
Don't you dare leave this house!
This is all your fault!
[tense music playing]
I will deal with you later.
Good-for-nothing people!
A good and honest politician
does not hide anything
from his constituents.
That is why I chose to face you
and to tell you honestly
that the viral video
involving me in a gambling scandal
is not true.
It was fabricated by people…
who want to ruin
my long and clean record
in public service.
So, now…
I am apologizing…
to every citizen of Poblacion Ardiente.
I apologize because
I let these people ruin…
[Loring] Diego, I know you said
that everyone is innocent
until proven guilty.
But what do you think about this?
[Diego] I don't know anything about this.
But I think everyone…
wants to believe in
the innocence of their family.
This is the first time I've seen
your grandfather like that.
He looks weak and aging.
I'll be worried if he starts
looking younger.
[Pandoy laughing]
[Loring] Come on, Pandoy.
There you go again!
You know what I mean!
I'm sure Grandpa is furious
with Dad again.
[reporter 1] But how do you explain
that your name is mentioned in the video?
[Julio chuckles] Come on.
We all know how advanced
technology is nowadays.
The voice on the video could
have been tampered with.
[reporter 2]
Let's say the audio was edited.
But how can you explain
the presence of Raul Torillo
in the footage?
You know, my friends…
not all families are perfect.
Mr. Raul Torillo has a gambling problem,
and we just found out recently.
The governor and her husband
are working on this problem.
Don't worry, it won't take long
until things return to normal.
[reporter 1]
Can we talk to Mr. Raul Torillo?
Where is he?
[Julio] Uh… They asked
that we respect their privacy
while they are coping with this situation.
[reporter 1] Drop the act, Congressman.
Present Mister Torillo.
We know you're hiding him.
[reporter 2] Yes, Congressman.
We need Mr. Torillo's statement
to validate all this.
[reporter 3] Are you hiding Mr. Torillo?
Why is that, Congressman?
[reporter 4] Is it true that you
have problems with Mr. Torillo?
[reporter 5] Is there a conflict
between you and Mr. Torillo?
Okay, that's it!
That's it! That ends our press conference.
Thank you so much for coming.
You may now leave.
-Thank you.
-Thank you, everyone.
-[Emilia] Papa.
-Hands off me!
This is you and your husband's fault!
[exhales]
Papa! Why are you all
blaming this on Raul?!
He isn't solely responsible for this.
I told you this press conference
won't do you any good,
but you still pushed through!
Emilia, I can't…
-Help your grandfather!
-[Ivy] Congressman.
[Emilia] My god!
Can you please take him to his room?
-[Julio] Arnaldo, come with me.
-[Arnaldo] Of course.
Is he okay?
[Emilia] Have you been there all long?
Uh… No, I just arrived.
I came as soon as I heard.
How's the situation?
[sighs] It's bad. It's really bad.
Everything is just taking a toll on Papa.
He won't listen to me.
But you know, I just have to thank you
that you urged me to speak up.
At least, I proved to myself
that my opinions are valid.
Papa just won't listen to me.
If he had listened to me,
this wouldn't have happened.
Governor, if you need someone to talk to,
I'm just here.
Thank you, Ivy. Thank you.
[Emilia] Looks like that lunatic
was right,
that the Ardiente household will fall!
Our empire is falling!
And I need to save it.
[sighs] Governor, why not ask for help?
Isn't the senator involved in this?
Ivy, please stop calling me "Governor"!
Emilia will do.
-Fine.
-And that Senator is another problem.
He won't answer our calls!
He knows this will backfire on all of us!
You know,
this is so frustrating!
Emilia, relax.
For sure, you can manage.
You'll find a way.
[sighs] Relax, okay?
I think I found a solution.
I see.
And I'm looking at her now.
What?
Me? Emilia!
Ivy, wait!
All you got to do
is just vouch for our name.
Just tell the public
that the Ardientes are good people.
That's why you're still investing in us.
-But Emilia, you know that--
-Ivy! Hear me out, okay?
Hear me out.
Just prove to everyone
that the Ardientes are good people,
that we are innocent.
You know, for somebody like you
who's got a stellar reputation,
people will listen!
But you are innocent, right?
The video is not true, right?
Tell me.
Emilia…
Ivy.
-You are my friend, right?
-Yes.
-I can trust you.
-Yes, Emilia.
That's why I'm going
to tell you the truth.
Ivy…
the video and the accusations against us…
are all true.
[Emilia sighs]
Now that you know the truth,
will you still help us?
How are you feeling?
I've been worse.
Don't worry, I'm fine.
I'll be okay…
as long as Raul doesn't show his face!
And your mother…
she's another headache.
I don't understand why of all times,
she chose to go against me now.
Calm down, Grandpa.
I will fix this.
We will fix this.
I'll talk to my parents and track down
whoever is messing with the Ardientes.
And I promise to make them pay.
I appreciate your honesty, Emilia.
At least, I know now…
with whom I'm trusting my money.
So, are you staying?
Are you pursuing your investment?
Thank you, Ivy! Thank you.
[exhales sharply]
[tense music playing]
All my life,
you have prepared me for this,
and I'll prove to you
that everything you taught me
will not go to waste.
Spoken like a true Ardiente.
You know, Arnaldo…
I'm grateful to have someone like you…
that I can depend on
in situations like this.
When I'm gone…
all this will be yours.
You will be the king
of Poblacion Ardiente.
Take good care of our name.
I will not disappoint you.
-Dad!
-[Raul] Hey.
Son!
Join me for a drink.
It's boring to be alone.
-You're not drinking alone.
-Why?
Those mosquitoes
are also chugging your blood.
That's what I like about you, son.
It's good you have a sense of humor.
Those people inside?
All they do is get mad.
They're all angry, especially with me.
Is that why you're outside?
[clicks tongue]
I've always been outside, son.
I've always been alone outside…
because this family never accepted me.
Welcome to the club.
You really are my son.
I saw the video.
I don't want to talk about that.
-But, Dad--
-I don't want to talk about it.
Give me a break, will you?
If you don't want to join me, that's fine.
Just go inside.
[Emilia on voice memo]
I'm going to tell you the truth.
Ivy…
the video and the accusations
against us are all true.
Now that you know the truth…
will you still help us?
[tense music playing]
The Ardiente's downfall is within reach.
[beeps]
Hey, Diego!
Glad to see you home.
I thought you'd joined
the critics of Grandpa.
Even though you do things
that I can hardly swallow…
I still love you all.
And I'll keep you all
out of trouble if I have to.
Papa.
-How are you feeling?
-I'm fine.
I've already taken my medicines.
Now, I need to rest.
Do you want a nurse to look after you?
Emilia.
Why are you being like this?
Why are you becoming a thorn in my side?!
What do you want?
Are you trying to prove something?
It's like you're trying to prove
that you can manage,
that you're already better
than me, is that it?
No. That we are equal, Papa!
That being a woman doesn't mean
I'm weaker than you.
Oh!
Women were created to be servants of men!
Don't wait for me to put you
in your proper place, Emilia!
Okay, that's good.
I'm expecting your help
to resolve our family problem.
Arnaldo, don't you think…
it's time for our family to change?
Let's turn away from these illegal things.
I'm not blind, Arnaldo.
I know the business of this family.
I know what's going on in this house.
I chose to keep quiet because I believe
that you can change--
We don't have to change anything, Diego.
Nothing.
We rule this town
because we have the power!
I don't understand
why you still can't grasp that.
In Ardiente, we are the rulers!
[Julio laughs]
Your faithful husband is finally here!
Do you see the consequences
of your actions?
Did you see how the media
disrespected me because of you?!
That wouldn't be the case
if you answered better.
Now you're also talking back, huh?!
-Have you forgotten--
-[Raul] I haven't forgotten.
That's why I'm telling you to also stop!
[Emilia] Raul, stop. That's enough!
[Julio laughing] Hey!
Go on! That's what you're good at!
Running after picking a fight,
and then hiding behind your wife.
Yes! Just let your wife save you again
from another one of your failures!
Oh, Raul.
It doesn't surprise me anymore
because you are that kind of man!
You are a good-for-nothing son of a--
[Julio grunting]
-[Raul] I'll kill you, bastard!
-[Julio grunting]
What are you doing, Raul?!
-[Raul growls]
-Stop it, Raul!
-[Raul] I'll kill you!
-Raul, stop it!
Raul, what are you doing?! Stop it! Stop!
-[Raul] What now?!
-[Emilia] Stop it!
[both grunting]
[Emilia] Papa!
Papa!
Papa? [crying]
[wailing] Papa!
Papa!
[Emilia] My time has come.
Now that the king is gone,
I shall reign as the queen.
[Diego] I've just noticed.
Whenever something bad
happens to my family,
you're always there.
Why are you so concerned about my family?
[Ivy] You shouldn't get dragged
into this, Diego.
But if you get in my way,
I'll have no choice
but to deal with you too.
[Raul] You know, Emilia, if you think
you can leash me forever,
then you are wrong.
I won't let you do that.
[Emilia] On the contrary,
I don't want you here.
You can stay with your relatives
if you still have any.
[Raul] Love, I'm back.
[theme music playing]